JONATHAN KOLYER

SOFTWARE
DEVELOPMENT
PROFESSIONAL

CONTACT DETAILS

Location: San Francisco Phone: 415-699-2175

Email Github LinkedIn

LANGUAGES

- TypeScript / JavaScript
- Python / Ruby / Java
- HTML/CSS
- SQL / GraphQL

SOME TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS

- AWS
- Kubernetes
- LangChain
- NodeJs
- React / React Native
- PostgreSQL / Redis / MongoDB
- Nx.dev
- Functional Programming

PROFILE

Seasoned developer & leader over 25 years – specializing in pattern-based architectures solving business problems

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Technical Leadership

Process and project management. SDLC. Product strategy.

Management

Team experience. Mentorship. Communications. Bootstrapping.

Software Design & Implementation

Cloud microservices. Chatbots. Mobile. GitOps. Media processing. Data pipelines. Monoliths.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineering Manager

QuickNode, Inc.

June 2022 - July 2023

- Grew applications team from zero to twenty ICs
- Supported applications team and six direct reports
- Managed monorepo infrastructure for a dozen applications
- Built out development cloud infrastructure on AWS
- Built out CI/CD pipeline for Kubernetes and ArgoCD
- Prototyped content generation tools with ChatGPT/LangChain

Principal Engineer

Chask.ai

September 2020 – June 2022

Developer of chatbot platform for group task management.

Head of Solutions Engineering

Doc.ai

January 2019 – May 2020

Technical lead for mobile engagements with **Anthem**.

Mobile Architect - IOS

TextNow

May 2017 - August 2018

Designed new chat interface framework for <u>telephony & messaging</u> platform. Introduced best practices and testing processes.

Founding Engineer

<u>JamKazam</u>

January 2013 - May 2018

Built a suite of applications for musicians to play together online.

Software Architect

<u>PayNearMe</u>

February 2014 – February 2017

Point-of-sale mobile and back-end applications.

Chief Technical Officer / Founding Engineer

PodOmatic

March 2005 – February 2013

Technical lead for podcasting social network wearing any hat necessary.

Previous Roles

1991 - 2013

- Actor represented by <u>Look Talent</u>
- SaleSorter CTO: retail sales aggregator start-up
- Bowstreet Solutions Architect: Cisco Systems engagement
- Moody's KMV Web Architect: Credit risk modelling
- Infoscape System Consultant: Java-based products
- Apple Consulting Engineer: On-site custom app development
- <u>AT&T Wireless</u>: Consulting engineer
- WhiteLight Systems: Lead developer
- NASA Ames: Research software engineer
- UC Berkeley: Research software engineer

EDUCATION

MS, Industrial Engineering & Operations Research University of California, Berkeley

1991

BA, Mathematics

Northwestern University

1987